<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mike John Page</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mike John Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash Aliases</title>
      <link>/blog/bash-alias/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/bash-alias/</guid>
      <description>In this quick post, I will show you how to make a bash alias. To understand what an alias does, Wikipedia provides a good definition:
 In computing, aliasing describes a situation in which a data location in memory can be accessed through different symbolic names in the program.
 In short, creating an alias in bash (the unix shell command language) allows you to type some specific keyword to run whatever you choose to alias (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rendering JavaScript content using Python, Selenium, and a Headless Browser</title>
      <link>/blog/rendering-javascript-content-using-python-selenium-and-a-headless-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/rendering-javascript-content-using-python-selenium-and-a-headless-browser/</guid>
      <description>This post will demonstrate how to scrape data from the web rendered in JavaScript (JS), using Python and several other tools. To achieve this, we will build a scraper that collects the current days weather forecast for a given location (rendered in JS) from Wunderground.
First, the robots.txt file on the Wunderground site must be inspected, in addition to the Terms of Service of the site, to see if scraping information is permitted:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 18.04 LTS &#43; Thinkpad X1 Carbon 6th Generation</title>
      <link>/blog/ubuntu-18-04-lts-thinkpad-x1-carbon-6th-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/ubuntu-18-04-lts-thinkpad-x1-carbon-6th-generation/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I will be listing some of the steps I took to set up Ubuntu 18.04 LTS on a Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Carbon 6th Gen. This includes installation steps, as well as post-installations packages I have found that I now use in my daily workflow. This serves to both remind myself of how to set up Ubuntu on future machines in a way I now deem to be near-optimal, and to also help others who may be having difficulty getting Ubuntu to run the way they would like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GGDOT Hacknight: using Box-Cox Transformations and Regression to Analyse the CO2 Emissions of Food</title>
      <link>/blog/ggdot-hacknight-using-box-cox-transformations-and-regression-to-analyse-the-co2-emissions-of-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/ggdot-hacknight-using-box-cox-transformations-and-regression-to-analyse-the-co2-emissions-of-food/</guid>
      <description>GGDOT HACKNIGHT The GGDOT project combines expertise in greenhouse gas emission calculations, nutrition, and data science to deliver a toolkit. This toolkit contains information on the greenhouse gas emissions and nutritional content of the food we eat. As part of the project, GGDOT host Hacknights to help develop their tools and analyse the data within them. I was fortunate enough to be able to attend the recent Manchester Hacknight, and this blog post will go through the analyses I performed from that session (and the day after).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phyllotaxis Project</title>
      <link>/blog/phyllotaxis-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/phyllotaxis-project/</guid>
      <description>Michael Page 
INFO This post isn’t so much a ‘blog’ post as it is a repository for me to store my code for the ‘Phyllotaxis: Draw flowers using mathematics’ project which can be found on DataCamp. Most of the code follows the standard solutions for the project, with the exception of using theme_void() to remove elements from a plot. In this case, using theme_void() is a more elegant solution (in my opinion) than independetly assigning element_blank() to each element (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multilevel Modelling in SPSS</title>
      <link>/blog/multilevel-modelling-in-spss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/multilevel-modelling-in-spss/</guid>
      <description>Michael Page 
INTRODUCTION Nested data structures When selecting an analysis for a given data set it is important to consider if the data is in a nested (i.e., hierarchical/clustered/grouped) structure. A nested data structure is one in which the data is organised at more than one level. For example, students can be nested within classes as so:
 In a similar fashion, it could be said that individual student test scores can be nested within students, who are nested within classes, which are nested within schools:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfectionism in the Public Domain: a Natural Language Processing Approach</title>
      <link>/projects/perfectionism-in-the-public-domain-a-natural-language-processing-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/perfectionism-in-the-public-domain-a-natural-language-processing-approach/</guid>
      <description>Michael Page 
1. INTRODUCTION 1.1 Introduction to the problem Recent meta-analytical evidence demonstrates that levels of perfectionism in Western populations has linearly increased over the past three decades (Curran &amp;amp; Hill, 2017). This has coincided with a rapid growth in the number of research articles investigating the outcomes, processes, and characteristics associated with perfectionism since the introduction of the first multidimensional perfectionism measures in the early 90’s. Despite a growing body of perfectionism literature in the academic domain, little is known (from the perspective of the academic) regarding reporting standards of perfectionism in the public domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Personal Statement A junior data scientist that is highly motivated, analytical, and revels on intellectual challenges. Has significant experience delivering a data workflow, from data collection, to implementing statistical and machine learning methods, to relevant and meaningful delivery of results. Excellent communicator who thrives in creating a story from data and works diligently in interdisciplinary teams to deliver timely results.
Relevant Skills Technologies: R, Python, MySQL, PostgresSQL, SPSS Statistics, Excel, Bash, G-Power, Git</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/</guid>
      <description> Data Scientist, Question Asker, and R Enthusiast. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>The MIT License (MIT)
Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 Michael Page
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>