<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mike John Page</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mike John Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfectionism in the Public Domain: a Natural Language Processing Approach</title>
      <link>/projects/perfectionism-in-the-public-domain-a-natural-language-processing-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/perfectionism-in-the-public-domain-a-natural-language-processing-approach/</guid>
      <description>Perfectionism in the Public Domain: a Natural Language Processing Approach Michael Page 
1. INTRODUCTION 1.1 Introduction to the problem Recent meta-analytical evidence demonstrates that levels of perfectionism in Western populations has linearly increased over the past three decades (Curran &amp;amp; Hill, 2017). This has coincided with a rapid growth in the number of research articles investigating the outcomes, processes, and characteristics associated with perfectionism since the introduction of the first multidimensional perfectionism measures in the early 90’s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Post</title>
      <link>/blog/test-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/test-post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A small project example : add yours !</title>
      <link>/projects/small-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/small-project/</guid>
      <description>Along with Ford Prefect, Dent barely escapes the Earth&amp;rsquo;s destruction as it is demolished to make way for a hyperspace bypass. Arthur spends the next several years, still wearing his dressing gown, helplessly launched from crisis to crisis while trying to straighten out his lifestyle.
 He rather enjoys tea, but seems to have trouble obtaining it in the far reaches of the galaxy.
 In time, he learns how to fly and carves a niche for himself as a sandwich-maker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Education  MSc by Research in Psychoendocrinology: York St John Universitry Sport Science Performance Conditionig BSc (hons): York St John Univeristy Introduction to Data Science: Springboard Data Scientist with R Career Track (12 modules): DataCamp  Publications  Multidimensional perfectionism and cortisol response in non-clinical populations: A systematic review and evaluation. Journal of Personality and Individual Differences Volume 124. April 2018.  Awards  Undergraduate: Dissertation prize. Highest course grade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 20:29:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/projects/</guid>
      <description>In this theme, it is possible to add sections like a Projects one for example. You can add plenty of articles about your projects and a presentation page that will be displayed before the list. All is modulable, if you don&amp;rsquo;t want something.
A Hollywood-funded film version, produced and filmed in the UK, was released in April 2005, and radio adaptations of the third, fourth, and fifth novels were broadcast from 2004 to 2005.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/</guid>
      <description> Data Scientist, Question Asker, and R Enthusiast. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>The MIT License (MIT)
Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 Michael Page
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>